<?xml-stylesheet href="/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Zephyr's Blog</title><link>https://zhangxume.github.io/en/</link><description>Recent content on Zephyr's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>2024 Zephyr. All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 19:03:18 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zhangxume.github.io/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Post 1</title><link>https://zhangxume.github.io/en/posts/post-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 19:03:18 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://zhangxume.github.io/en/posts/post-1/</guid><description>Zephyr's Blog https://zhangxume.github.io/en/posts/post-1/ -&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This is &lt;strong>bold&lt;/strong> text, and this is &lt;em>emphasized&lt;/em> text.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Visit the &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io">Hugo&lt;/a> website!&lt;/p>
- https://zhangxume.github.io/en/posts/post-1/ - 2024 Zephyr. All rights reserved.</description></item><item><title>IELTS Self Study Guide</title><link>https://zhangxume.github.io/en/posts/ielts-self-study-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 13:03:04 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://zhangxume.github.io/en/posts/ielts-self-study-guide/</guid><description>Zephyr's Blog https://zhangxume.github.io/en/posts/ielts-self-study-guide/ -&lt;h1 id="preface">Preface&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Firstly, it&amp;rsquo;s important to understand the overall structure of the IELTS exam and dedicate a substantial amount of time specifically for IELTS preparation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>IELTS consists of four sections: Listening, Reading, Writing, and Speaking.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Learning any content is an accumulative process, and this article only applies to short-term rapid learning.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h1 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="listening">Listening&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Listening section lasts for 30 minutes and includes 4 recorded monologues and conversations. For paper-based exams, there&amp;rsquo;s time allocated to transfer answers to an answer sheet. This step is unnecessary for computer-based exams.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="reading">Reading&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Reading section lasts for 60 minutes and includes 3 passages with corresponding questions. Some passages may also include diagrams or charts.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="writing">Writing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Writing section also lasts for 60 minutes. The first task involves writing a 150-word essay based on a table or graph. The second task requires writing a 250-word discursive essay based on a given topic.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="speaking">Speaking&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Speaking section lasts for approximately 10-15 minutes and involves face-to-face questions and conversations.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="method">Method&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="listening-1">Listening&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I started by practicing listening comprehension using physical copies of Cambridge IELTS materials and online resources.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="reading-1">Reading&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I familiarized myself with various types of articles and questions by completing full practice exams. The focus was on quickly locating and understanding key information within the passages.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="writing-1">Writing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I referred to sample essays to understand how to structure responses according to different task requirements and effectively express logical viewpoints.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="speaking-1">Speaking&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Speaking primarily involves question-and-answer sessions, observing what questions might be asked and how others respond. The aim is not to memorize responses but to learn how to extend a topic, express your viewpoints clearly. For instance, if asked about your favorite color, simply stating the color isn&amp;rsquo;t enough; explain why you like it. The focus is on practicing conversation skills and articulating your thoughts effectively.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In conclusion, the computer-based testing experience is favorable.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="tips">Tips&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The computer-based testing process includes check-in, waiting areas, verification zones, and the exam area. The procedures are generally similar across all test centers. The Speaking test is conducted separately and requires a separate appointment.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Test centers provide earplugs and pens, so there&amp;rsquo;s no need to worry about external distractions. Some newly opened centers may have fewer people, making it easier to schedule appointments.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
- https://zhangxume.github.io/en/posts/ielts-self-study-guide/ - 2024 Zephyr. All rights reserved.</description></item></channel></rss>